《加勒比海盗2: 亡灵宝藏》
威尔
Will!
- 这是怎么回事? - 我不知道
- Why is this happening? - I don't know.
你看起来真美
You look beautiful.
婚礼前让新郎见到新娘是厄运之兆
It's bad luck for the groom to see the bride before the wedding.
闪开 让我过去 大胆
Make way! Let me through! How dare you!
马上让你的人滚蛋 听见没?
Stand your men down at once. Do you hear me?
韦瑟比·斯旺总督 久违啦
Governor Weatherby Swann, it's been too long.
- 卡特勒·贝克特? - 现在是贝克特勋爵了
- Cutler Beckett? - It's Lord now, actually.
不管你是不是勋爵 你没有理由 也没有权利逮捕这位先生
Lord or not, you have no reason and no authority to arrest this man.
事实上 我有 玛萨先生?
In fact, I do. Mr Mercer?
我有授权 逮捕人犯威廉·特纳
The warrant for the arrest of one William Turner.
- 这个逮捕证是伊丽莎白·斯旺的 - 是吗? 真麻烦 是我的错
- This warrant is for Elizabeth Swann. - Is it? That's annoying. My mistake.
- 把她抓起来 - 罪名是什么?
- Arrest her. - On what charges?
这是威廉·特纳的
Aha. Here's the one for William Turner.
我还有另外一张 是詹姆斯·诺灵顿先生的
And I have another one for a Mr James Norrington.
- 他在这吗? - 罪名是什么?
- Is he present? - What are the charges?
诺灵顿司令官数月前辞职了
Commodore Norrington resigned his commission some months ago.
我觉得这不是我要问的
That wasn't the answer to the question I asked.
贝克特勋爵 你的问题不会被回答的
Lord Beckett. In the category of questions not answered...
我们归国王陛下在皇家港的总督管辖
We are under the jurisdiction of the king's governor of Port Royal
你得说清楚我们的罪名是什么
and you will tell us what we are charged with.
罪名是...
The charge is "conspiring to set free
阴谋释放一名触犯了帝国法律的死囚
a man convicted of crimes against the Crown and Empire
而对此...
and condemned to death, for which the..."
而对此的惩罚 很遗憾 也是死刑
For which the punishment, regrettably, is also death.
也许你们还记得某个 名叫杰克·斯派洛的海盗
Perhaps you remember a certain pirate named Jack Sparrow.
船长
Captain.
杰克·斯派洛船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
没错 我就知道你们记得
Yes, I thought you might.
∮ 亡灵箱上十五人坐 ∮
∮ Fifteen men on a dead man's chest ∮
∮ 嘿呦吼吼 来瓶朗姆酒 ∮
∮ Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum ∮
∮ 干一杯啊 剩下的留给魔鬼 ∮
∮ Drink and the devil had done for the rest ∮
∮ 嘿呦吼吼 来瓶朗姆酒 ∮
∮ Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum ∮
囚犯们 过来
Prisoners, come on!
兄弟 对不起啦
Sorry, mate.
介意伴我一游吗?
Mind if we make a little side trip?
我想你不会介意的
I didn't think so.
- 似乎计划有变啊? - 临时有变
- Not quite according to plan. - Complications arose, ensued,
还好我随机应变
were overcome.
你找到要找的东西了吗?
You got what you went in for, then?
船长 我觉得船员们 也包括我
Captain, I think the crew, meaning me as well,
我们想要些亮闪闪的东西
were expecting something a bit more shiny,
如果死亡岛 带着上面的财宝 又沉入大海怎么办?
with the lsla de Muerta going pear-shaped, reclaimed by the sea with the treasure.
皇家海军还在满大西洋上追我们
And the Royal Navy chasing us around the Atlantic.
- 还有飓风 - 是啊 是啊
- And the hurricane. - Aye.
总之 我们似乎有一阵没干海盗的本行啦
All in all, it seems some time since we did a speck of honest pirating.
- 闪亮的? - 没错 闪亮的
- Shiny. - Aye, shiny.
这就是你们想要的吗?
Is that how you're all feeling?
也许老杰克没兴趣当你们的船长
That perhaps dear old Jack is not serving your best interests as captain?
啊 走木板吧
Walk the plank.
- 那鸟说啥? - 别怨鸟了
- What did the bird say? - Do not blame the bird.
给我们看看那块布上有什么
Show us what is on that piece of cloth there.
- 这么干可不好 - 对我来说不错
- You know that don't do no good. - It does me.
- 是把钥匙 - 不 钥匙怎么比得上这个
- It's a key. - No. Much more better.
这可是一把钥匙的图样
It is a drawing of a key.
先生们
Gentlemen,
钥匙是用来干嘛的呢?
what do keys do?
钥匙
Keys
能开锁?
unlock things?
不管这钥匙开的是什么锁 里面一定有值钱的东西
And whatever this key unlocks, inside there's something valuable.
所以我们要出发找到这钥匙能开的锁?
So we're setting out to find whatever this key unlocks.
不对
No.
没有它 不管那是什么锁 我们也打不开
If we don't have the key, we can't open whatever we don't have that it unlocks.
不先搞到钥匙 找到锁又有何用?
So what purpose would be served in finding whatever need be unlocked,
且不说咱们手上还没锁!
which we don't have, without first having found the key what unlocks it?
就是说...我们要找钥匙罗?
So we're going after this key.
你的话完全不合理
You're not making any sense at all.
还有什么问题吗?
Any more questions?
那 我们有航向吗?
So do we have a heading?
啊 航向
A heading.
升帆向...
Set sail in a
大概...
general
朝那个方向
that-way direction.
船长?
Captain?
快点起航 你们知道怎么做
Come on, snap to and make sail. You know how this works. Go on.
你注意到了没有?
Have you noticed lately
船长好像有点怪
the captain seems to be acting a bit strange... er?
连航向都不知道就起航
Setting sail without knowing his own heading.
肯定有什么东西让他心事重重
Something's got Jack vexed, and mark my words,
要我说 杰克·斯派洛都不知所措 一定不是好兆头
what bodes ill for Jack Sparrow bodes ill for us all.
贝克特勋爵 囚犯带到
Lord Beckett, the prisoner as ordered, sir.
去掉镣铐
Those won't be necessary.
东印度公司需要你的服务
The East lndia Trading Company has need of your services.
我们希望你可以作为我们的代理人
We wish for you to act as our agent
和我们共同的朋友斯派洛船长谈笔生意
in a business transaction with our mutual friend Captain Sparrow.
我们只是认识 谈不上是朋友 你怎么认识他的?
More acquaintance. How do you know him?
我们过去打过交道
We've had dealings in the past.
我们都给对方留下了自己的印记
And we've each left our mark on the other.
他给你留下什么印记了?
What mark did he leave on you?
因为你 杰克·斯派洛才得到自由
By your efforts, Jack Sparrow was set free.
我想要你找到他
I would like you to go to him
从他那拿件财物回来
and recover a certain property in his possession.
拿回? 用剑逼他吗?
Recover. At the point of a sword?
谈条件
Bargain.
私掠许可
Letters of marque.
你的刑罚将被完全赦免
You will offer what amounts to a full pardon.
杰克将获得自由 成为英国雇佣的私掠船长
Jack will be free, a privateer in the employ of England.
我有点怀疑杰克会认为 雇佣等同于自由
Somehow I doubt Jack will consider employment the same as being free.
自由
Freedom.
杰克·斯派洛这类人必将消亡
Jack Sparrow is a dying breed.
世界越来越小了
The world is shrinking,
地图边界的上空白越来越少
the blank edges of the map filled in.
杰克要不就在新世界找到自己的位置 不然就死路一条
Jack must find his place in the New World or perish.
你和他不同 特纳先生
Not unlike you, Mr Turner.
你和你的未婚妻将面临绞刑
You and your fiancee face the hangman's noose.
- 就是说杰克和黑珍珠号你都要? - 黑珍珠号?
- So you get Jack and the Black Pearl. - The Black Pearl?
- 你要他的船 - 一条船?
- The property you want that he possesses. - A ship? Hardly.
我要的东西要小得多 但也值钱得多
The item in question is considerably smaller and far more valuable,
斯派洛总是随身带着的一件东西
something Sparrow keeps on his person at all times.
一个罗盘
A compass?
你知道这件东西
You know it.
把那罗盘弄回来 不然这交易就作废
Bring back that compass or there's no deal.
怎么朗姆酒总是喝光?
Why is the rum always gone?
原来这么回事
That's why.
继续 先生们
As you were, gents.
时光飞逝啊 杰克
Time's run out, Jack.
系带王
Bootstrap.
比尔·特纳
Bill Turner.
你看上去不错啊 杰克
You look good, Jack.
这是梦吗?
Is this a dream?
不是
No.
我想也不是 不然就会有朗姆酒了
I thought not. If it were, there'd be rum.
看来你夺回"珍珠"了
You got the Pearl back, I see.
有人帮我夺回了"珍珠"号
I had some help retrieving the Pearl, by the way.
你的儿子
Your son.
威廉?
William?
最后还是干上了海盗
He ended up a pirate after all.
我欠你这老瘤子什么情吗?
And to what do I owe the pleasure of your carbuncle?
是"他"派我来的
He sent me.
戴维·琼斯
Davy Jones.
啊 原来是这样
So it's you, then.
他把你骗上贼船的 对吧?
He shanghaied you into service, eh?
我选的
I chose it.
我很抱歉 针对你的那次叛乱中 我没干什么好事 杰克
I'm sorry for the part I played in the mutiny against you, Jack.
我是支持你的
I stood up for you.
那之后一切都乱套了
Everything went wrong after that.
他们把我绑到一尊大炮上 沉到海底
They strapped me to a cannon. I ended up on the bottom of the ocean,
海水压得我死死的
the weight of the water crushing down on me.
动也动不了
Unable to move.
死也死不成 杰克
Unable to die, Jack.
即使是一丝能摆脱这种命运的机会 我也会抓住不放的
And I thought that even the tiniest hope of escaping this fate, I would take it.
我会用一切来交换的
I would trade anything for it.
一个人为了逃避最终审判 真是什么事都干得出啊
It's funny what a man will do to forestall his final judgment.
你也和他做了交易 杰克
You made a deal with him too, Jack.
他替你将"珍珠"号从海底拉了上来
He raised the Pearl from the depths for you.
你可是做了它13年的船长
13 years, you've been her captain.
- 准确来说... - 杰克
- Technically... - Jack.
靠嘴皮子你是甩不脱的
You won't be able to talk yourself out of this.
对我适用的条款 对你也适用
The terms what applied to me apply to you as well.
有个灵魂 注定要在这船上服务一百年
One soul bound to crew 100 years upon his ship.
"飞翔的荷兰人" 已经有个船长
The Flying Dutchman already has a captain...
所以你也跑不了
Then it's the locker for you!
琼斯的大海怪会找到你的
Jones's terrible leviathan will find you
把你和"珍珠"号一起拖回海底
and drag the Pearl back to the depths and you along with it.
你知道琼斯什么时候 会派所谓的大海怪来吗?
Any idea when Jones might release said terrible beastie?
我告诉过你了 杰克
I already told you, Jack.
你的劫数已尽
Your time is up.
它现在就来了
It comes now,
如饿鬼般的贪婪 直奔带有黑斑的人
drawn with ravenous hunger to the man what bears the black spot.
所有人上甲板 赶快拉紧束帆索
On deck, all hands! Make fast the bunt gasket!
小子们 快点
On deck! Scurry!
快点 快起航
Scurry! I want movement! Movement! I want movement!
起帆 稳舵 扬帆
Lift the skin up! Keep your loof! Haul those sheets!
跑 快跑 恶魔就追在我们后面
Run them! Run! Keep running! Run as if the devil himself and itself is upon us!
- 我们有航向吗? - 启动 朝向陆地
- Do we have a heading? - Run! Land.
- 哪个港口? - 我没说港口 我说的是陆地 任何陆地
- Which port? - I didn't say "port", I said "land". Any land.
- 杰克的帽子 弄上来 - 别 别
- Jack's hat! Bring her about! - No, no!
别管那个了
Leave it!
快跑
Run.
回到岗位上去 都回去
Back to your stations, the lot of you!
杰克?
Jack?
看在圣母和圣子的份上 到底是什么东西在追我们啊?
For the love of mother and child, Jack, what's coming after us?
没什么
Nothing.
- 你不能待在这儿 - 你会知道他可以待在这
- Here, now, you can't be here. - I think you'll find he can.
斯旺先生
Mr Swann!
我还是斯旺总督
Governor Swann, still.
你以为我戴这头假发是为了保暖吗
Do you think I wear this wig to keep my head warm?
杰克的罗盘? 贝克特要那东西干什么?
Jack's compass? What does Beckett want with that?
无关紧要 我要去找到杰克 说服他回皇家港
Does it matter? I'm to find Jack and convince him to return to Port Royal.
这样对我们的起诉就能撤销
In exchange, the charges against us will be dropped.
不 你们能否获得自由 不能操于他人之手
No. We must find our own avenue to secure your freedom.
你是对杰克没信心 还是对我没信心?
Is that a lack of faith in Jack or in me?
你愿意牺牲自己的性命去救斯派洛
That you would risk your life to save Sparrow
不意味着他愿意为其他人做同样的事
does not mean he would do the same for anyone else.
那条有钥匙的狗跑哪去了?
Now, where is that dog with the keys?
我对你们有信心
I have faith in you.
你们两个
Both of you.
你到哪去找他?
Where will you find him?
从托图加岛找起 不找到他绝不罢休
Tortuga. I'll start there and I won't stop searching till I find him.
然后我会回来这里娶你
And then I intend to return here to marry you.
- 正式的? - 明媒正娶 如果你还要我的话
- Properly? - Eagerly, if you'll still have me.
如果不是这铁栏杆 我早就是你的人了
If it weren't for these bars, I'd have you already.
- 我会等你的 - 盯着海平线吧
- I'll wait for you. - Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
杰克·斯派洛船长?
Captain Jack Sparrow?
欠我4个金币 听说他死了
Owes me four doubloons. Heard he was dead.
我听说在新加坡 喝醉了 当时他脸上还带着笑
Singapore. That's what I heard. Drunk, with a smile on his face.
确信 杰克·斯派洛在新加坡出现了
Sure as the tide, Jack Sparrow turn up in Singapore.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow?
我一个月没见他了
I haven't seen him in a month.
等你找到他 帮我带个口信给他好吗?
When you find him, will you give him a message?
杰克的事我说不好
Can't say about Jack Sparrow,
但离海峡南面不远处有个小岛
but there's an island just south of the straits
我在那里用香料换...
where I trade spice for
喷香的羊肉
delicious long pork.
杰克我说不好 但你能在那找到一条船
Cannot say about Jack, but you'll find a ship there.
一条挂黑帆的船
A ship with black sails.
我叫人带你上岸
My brother will take you ashore.
- 有什么问题吗? 那儿就是海滩了 - [法语]
- What's wrong? The beach is there. - C'est trop dangereux.
- 什么? - [法语]
- What? - C'est trop dangereux. je vous l'avais dit.
[法语] 再见 先生
Bon voyage. monsieur.
杰克
Jack!
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow!
马蒂
Marty!
科顿
Cotton!
有人吗?
Anybody?
熟面孔
A familiar face.
别吃我
Don't eat me.
- 我不会吃你的 - 别吃我
- I'm not going to eat you. - Don't eat me.
不 别吃我
No. Don't eat me.
吉布斯
Gibbs.
我们走
Come on! Let's go!
来啊 谁想来?
Come on! Who wants it?
我整天都可以战斗
I can do this all day!
杰克
Jack?
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow!
能见到你我真是太高兴了
I can honestly say I'm glad to see you.
杰克 是我啊
Jack, it's me.
威尔·特纳
Will Turner.
让他们把我放下
Tell them to let me down!
杰克 那个罗盘 我只要那个
Jack, the compass. That's all I need.
伊丽莎白有危险 我们因为帮你被捕了
Elizabeth is in danger. We were arrested for helping you.
她会上绞架的
She faces the gallows!
是吗?
Savvy?
救我
Save me.
杰克 你对他们说什么了
Jack, what did you tell them?
不
No!
伊丽莎白怎么办?
What about Elizabeth?
杰克
Jack!
那是个好女孩 走进来些
That's a good girl. Come a little closer.
- 我们不咬 - 过来 我们不咬你
- We don't bite. - Go on. We won't bite you.
快点
Come quickly.
- 告诉我发生什么了? - 我们还有一点名气
- Tell me what's happening. - Our name still has some standing.
我安排你去英格兰 船长是我的朋友
I've arranged passage to England. The captain is a friend of mine.
不 威尔会找到杰克的
No! Will's gone to find Jack!
我们不能指望威廉·特纳
We cannot count on William Turner.
- 快点 - 他比你想像的要强得多
- Come! - He's better than you give him credit for.
现在没时间讨论他 贝克特只愿意赦免一个人
This is no time for innocence. Beckett has offered one pardon only...
那是对杰克·斯派洛的承诺
one, and that is promised to Jack Sparrow.
即使威尔成功了
Even if Will succeeds,
你也不能让我 亲眼看我的女儿去送死
do not ask me to endure the sight of my daughter walking to the gallows. Do not.
也许 等威尔回来的时候 我可以保证对他进行公平的审判
Perhaps I can ensure a fair trial for Will if he returns.
- 对他的公平审判就是要吊死他 - 到时 你就没什么你牵挂的了
- A fair trial for Will ends in a hanging. - Then there is nothing left for you here.
在里面等
Wait inside.
船长?
Captain?
船长
Captain.
晚上好 总督大人
Evening, Governor.
可惜啊
Shame, that.
他随身带着这个
He was carrying this.
一封给国王的信
It's a letter to the king.
- 你写的 - 不是
- It's from you. - No...
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
- 她在哪? - 谁?
- Where is she? - Who?
看来你已经意识到忠诚没什么用了
No doubt you've discovered that loyalty is no longer the currency of the realm,
不像你父亲那个死脑筋
as your father believes.
那什么才有用呢?
Then what is?
恐怕只有金钱才能通行无阻
I'm afraid currency is the currency of the realm.
我想这样我们应该能达成某种共识
I expect, then, we can come to some sort of understanding.
- 我是来谈判的 - 我在听
- I'm here to negotiate. - I'm listening.
我在仔细地听
I'm listening intently.
这些私掠许可是国王签署的
These letters of marque are signed by the king.
是的 不过没有我签字盖章 它们就不生效
Yes, and they're not valid until they bear my signature and my seal.
不然我也不会还待在这里了
Or else I would not still be here.
你派威尔去找杰克·斯派洛要罗盘
You sent Will to get you the compass owned by Jack Sparrow.
- 这对你不会有好处 - 请解释一下
- It will do you no good. - Do explain.
我去过死亡之岛 我亲眼见过那些财宝
I have been to the lsla de Muerta. I have seen the treasure myself.
- 有些东西你需要了解 - 我懂了
- There is something you need to know. - I see.
你以为那罗盘只是指向死亡之岛
You think the compass leads only to the lsla de Muerta
所以你希望能挽救我免遭厄运困扰
and so you hope to save me from an evil fate.
但你不用担心
But you mustn't worry.
我不想要那受诅咒的阿兹特克黄金
I care not for cursed Aztec gold.
我的眼光没有那么短浅
My desires are not so provincial.
在这片水域中 值钱的箱子不只一个
There's more than one chest of value in these waters.
所以我认为你应该提高出价
So perhaps you may wish to enhance your offer.
计算的时候别忘了 你还搅了我的新婚之夜
Consider into your calculations that you robbed me of my wedding night.
这倒是没错
So I did.
婚礼横遭打断
A marriage interrupted
是否天意如此呢?
or fate intervenes?
我们在尽力确保杰克·斯派洛的自由
You're making great efforts to ensure Jack Sparrow's freedom.
- 这不仅仅是为了杰克 - 是吗?
- These aren't going to Jack. - Really?
要想确保特纳先生的自由
To ensure Mr Turner's freedom, then,
我还是要那个罗盘
I'll still want that compass.
计算的时候别忘了这点
Consider that in your calculations.
我觉得能从监狱逃走 是上帝保佑的结果
I say it was Divine Providence what escaped us from jail.
我觉得幸亏是我比较聪明
And I say it was me being clever.
对不对 普奇?
Ain't that right, poochie?
你怎么知道你的小聪明 就不是上帝保佑的结果?
Well, how'd you know it weren't Divine Providence what inspired you to be clever?
不管怎样 我再不偷别人的船了
Anyways, I ain't stealing no ship.
那不是偷 是救援 什么时候你开始在意这个了?
It ain't stealing. It's salvaging. And since when did you care?
自从我们不再是不死之身 我们得考虑一下世俗的灵魂了
Since we're not immortal no more. We gotta take care of our immortal souls.
- 你知道你也看不懂 - 这可是圣经 试着读也会有奖励的
- You know you can't read. - It's the Bible. You get credit for trying.
装作在读圣经是一种谎言 这种行为会触怒...
Pretending to read the Bible's a lie. That's a mark against...
看啊
Look.
它在那
There it is.
它倒底怎么了?
What's got into him?
一定是见到鲶鱼了
Must have seen a catfish.
蠢货
Stupid mongrel!
来啊
Come on!
- 这归我们啦 - 正巧涨潮了 大好时机啊
- It's ours for the taking. - Tide's coming in. That should help.
从某种角度来说 救援船也是救赎啊
And salvaging is saving, in a manner of speaking.
没错
There's the truth of it!
我看我们应该尽快"救赎"它
Suppose we better save it as soon as we can,
我们的肉体现在很脆弱
what with our souls in such a vulnerable state and all.
阿门
Amen to that.
谢谢
Thank you.
他干嘛要这么对我们? 如果杰克是酋长的话?
Why would he do this to us? If Jack is the chief...
土著们的确让杰克作了酋长
Aye, the Pelegostos made Jack their chief,
只有酋长装得像样 他才能继续做下去
but he only remains chief as long as he acts like a chief.
就是说他别无选择 他像我们其他人一样也不过是个囚犯
So he had no choice. He's a captive as much as the rest of us.
事实上是更糟 土著认为杰克是附体的神灵
Worse, as it turns out. See, the Pelegostos believe that Jack is a god in human form,
他们想要把他 从现在的肉体中释放出来
and they intend to do him the honour of releasing him from his fleshy prison.
他们会把他烤来吃了
They'll roast him and eat him.
其他船员哪里去了?
Where's the rest of the crew?
关我们的这些笼子 是我们来了才造的
These cages we're in weren't built till after we got here.
宴会就要开始了
The feast is about to begin.
鼓声一停
Jack's life will end
杰克就要没命了
when the drums stop.
那我们不能就待在这等着吧?
Well, we can't just sit here and wait, then, can we?
不 不 不
No, no. Oi! No, no.
多弄点木头来 燃大火
More wood. Big fire. Big fire.
我是酋长 要燃大火
I am Chief. Want big fire.
快点
Come on.
木头 快点 多弄点木头
Tout de suite. Come on. More wood.
糟糕
Bugger.
得调调味 对吧
A little seasoning, eh?
干得不错
Well done.
把腿伸出去 开始爬啊
Put your legs through. Start to climb!
加油啊 驾驶"黑珍珠" 需要这里所有的人啊
Come on, men! It'll take all of us to crew the Black Pearl!
其实不需要那么多人
Actually, you wouldn't need everyone.
有六个就足够了
About six would do.
哦 天啊
Oh, dear.
- 快啊 - 快啊
- Hurry! - Come on!
快点 你们就这么点本事?
Come on! Is that all you got?
等等 停下来
Wait. Stop.
停下来
Stop.
- 他们在在做什么? - 停下来
- What are they doing? - Stop.
有蛇
Snake!
快走
Move!
去啊 去抓住他们
Well, go on, go get them.
哦 不 不
No, no. Oi! No, no!
不妙
Not good.
找石头把它切断
Cut it loose! Find a rock!
让笼子滚起来
Roll the cage!
快点
Come on!
- 快点把笼子抬起来 - 快提起来 就像提女人的裙子一样
- Lift the cage! Hurry! - Come on, lads. Lift it like a lady's skirt.
跑
Run!
这边
This way, lads!
小心
Take cover!
停手
Stop it!
糟糕
Bugger.
拉起驳船缆绳
Haul loose the mooring line!
缆绳
The mooring line!
小偷 毛头小偷 还给我
Thief! Little hairy thief! Give it back!
- 不要咬 - 拉起驳船缆绳
- Don't bite it! - Haul loose the mooring line!
他拿走我的眼睛不还
He's got me eye. He won't give it back.
- 我们下次再拿回来 可以吗? - 非常好 我们的工作完成一半了
- How'd you get it back last time? - Excellent! Our work's half done.
我们都是为你做的 知道你会回来了
We done it for you, knowing you'd be coming back.
- 准备开船 伙计们 - 杰克呢?
- Make ready to sail, boys! - What about Jack?
我不能丢下他
I won't leave without him.
- 该走了 - 放下缆绳
- Time to go. - Cast off those lines!
放下缆绳
Make ready to cast off!
乖狗狗
Good doggy.
你们应该永远记住今天
Alas, my children, this is the day you shall always remember as the day you almost...
你们差点捉到杰克·斯派洛船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
我们赶快远离这座岛并航向大海吧
Let's get away from this island and head out to open sea.
我同意 我同意 但我们不能离开浅滩太远
Yes to the first. Yes to the second, but only insofar as we keep to the shallows.
这似乎有点矛盾 船长
That seems a bit contradictory, Captain.
我对你的"和解式"导航法相当有信心
I have faith in your reconciliatory navigational skills.
那只猴子跑哪去了 我想找它练靶子
Now, where is that monkey? I want to shoot something.
杰克 伊莉莎白有危险
Jack. Elizabeth is in danger.
你有没有考虑过把她关起来
Have you considered just locking her up somewhere?
她为了你现在被捉起来 即将被吊死
She is locked up, bound to hang for helping you.
有时候人必须为了自己做错的事负责的
There comes a time when one must take responsibility for one's mistakes.
我需要你的罗盘 杰克
I need that compass of yours, Jack.
我要拿它去换取她的自由
I must trade it for her freedom.
- 吉布斯 - 船长
- Mr Gibbs. - Captain.
我们需要沿河逆流而上
We have a need to travel upriver.
你的"需要"是否只是你 一时兴起想到的小小愿望呢?
By need, do you mean a trifling need?
不 我指的是很肯定
Fleeting? As in, say, a passing fancy?
是不可更改的"需要"
No, a resolute and unyielding need.
我们现在需要的是即刻回到皇家港
What we need to do is make sail for Port Royal with all haste.
威廉
William,
我可以把罗盘给你
I shall trade you the compass
如果你帮我
if you will help me
帮我找到这个的话
to find this.
- 你要我帮你找这个? - 不
- You want me to find this? - No.
是你自己想要找这个
You want you to find this,
因为找到这个的话
because the finding of this finds you incapacitorially finding
你便会在无尽的探索中发现到 解救你那位小甜心的方法
and/or locating in your discovering a way to save your dolly belle, ol' what's-her-face.
知道吗?
Savvy?
这个东西可以解救伊莉莎白
This is going to save Elizabeth?
你对戴维·琼斯了解多少?
How much do you know about Davy Jones?
不多
Not much.
没错 这东西可以救伊莉莎白
Yeah, it's going to save Elizabeth.
搞什么飞机?
What's all this?
你们都那么喜欢那件洋装的话 就轮流穿
If you both fancy the dress, you'll just have to share and wear it one after the other.
不是这样的 船长 这艘船闹鬼了
It's not like that, sir. This ship is haunted.
是吗? 你说
Is it, now? And you?
这船上有个女鬼 先生
There's a female presence amongst us here, sir.
所有人都感觉到了
All the men, they can feel it.
我想是一位还未结婚便成了寡妇的女
It's the ghost of a lady widowed before her marriage, I figure it,
来这船上找她死在海上的丈夫了
searching for her husband, lost at sea.
她还是个处女 可能也不是
A virgin too, likely as not.
这是厄运之兆
And that bodes ill by all accounts.
我建议我们把这衣服丢下海 祈祷女鬼会跟着一起走
I say that we throw the dress overboard and we hope the spirit follows it.
不行 那只会激怒她
No! That will just anger the spirit, sir.
我们应搞清楚她想要什么 助她达成愿望
What we need to do is find out what the spirit needs, and then get it back to her.
够了 够了
Enough! Enough!
你们已经迷信到昏头了
You're a pair of superstitious goats and it's got the best of you.
由这看来我们船上来了一位不速之客
Now, this appears to be no more as we have a stowaway on board.
一个年轻女人
A young woman, by the look of it.
我要你们搜索全船把她找出来
I want you to search the ship and find her.
对了 她大概是一丝不挂的
Oh, and she's probably naked.
为何杰克这么怕大海?
Why is Jack afraid of the open ocean?
嗯 有这么一个传说
Well, if you believe such things,
戴维·琼斯的手下有一只怪兽
there's a beast does the bidding of Davy Jones...
它有着巨大的触手 一下就能把你的脸给吸下来
a fearsome creature with giant tentacles that'll suction your face clean off
然后把整艘船拉进海底深渊
and drag an entire ship down to the crushing darkness.
挪威海怪
The kraken.
就连它的呼吸...
They say the stench of its breath is like...
想像你临死之前听到的...
Imagine, the last thing you know on God's green earth
是它震耳欲聋的咆哮 闻到的是它腐尸般恶臭的呼吸
is the roar of the kraken and the reeking odour of a thousand rotting corpses.
如果你相信这传说的话
If you believe such things.
钥匙可以帮他解脱吗?
And the key will spare him that?
那正是杰克想知道的
Well, that's the very question Jack wants answered.
甚至不惜去问"她"
Bad enough even to go visit
"她"
her.
她?
Her?
对
Aye.
别担心 兄弟们 我跟蒂亚会回来的
No worries, mates. Tia Dalma and I go way back.
我们是如此地分不开
Thick as thieves. Nigh inseparable, we are.
曾经
Were. Have been.
以前
Before.
- 我会帮你提防后面 - 我怕的是她从正面来
- I'll watch your back. - It's me front I'm worried about.
- 看好船 - 看好船
- Mind the boat. - Mind the boat.
看好船
Mind the boat.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
提亚·朵玛
Tia Dalma.
我就知道总有一天风会把你吹回来
I always knew the wind was going to blow you back to me one day.
你...
You...
你对你的命运
You have a touch of
有预感
destiny about you,
威廉·特纳
William Turner.
你认识我?
You know me?
你想认识我
You want to know me.
我们有求而来 不达目的是不会走的
There'll be no knowing here. We've come for help and we're not leaving without it.
- 我以为我已经认识你 - 似乎不如我预期的那样
- I thought I knew you. - Not so well as I had hoped.
- 来 - 来
- Come. - Come.
我能怎样为你效劳?
What service may I do you?
- 你知道我需要报酬的 - 我带了报酬来
- You know I demand payment. - I brought payment.
瞧
Look.
不死猴
An undead monkey.
搁在上面了
Top that.
不要 你不知道我们花了多久才抓到它的
Don't! You've no idea how long it took us to catch that.
这个报酬很合理
The payment is fair.
我们在找这个东西
We're looking for this.
还有它所开启的东西
And what it goes to.
你之前从我这里得到的罗盘 无法帮你找到这钥匙的所在吗?
The compass you bartered from me, it cannot lead you to this?
也许可以 为什么?
Maybe. Why?
杰克·斯派洛也不知道自己在找什么
Jack Sparrow does not know what he wants.
或者你知道
Or do you know,
却不愿自己承认 是吗?
but are loath to claim it as your own?
这把钥匙可以开启一个宝箱
Your key go to a chest.
宝箱里的东西才是你们在寻找的 对吧?
And it is what lay inside the chest you seek, don't it?
- 里面到底是什么 - 金子?
- What is inside? - Gold?
珠宝? 或无人认领的贵重物品?
Jewels? Unclaimed properties of a valuable nature?
我希望 不是什么坏东西吧?
Nothing bad, I hope?
你们知道戴维·琼斯吗?
You know of Davy Jones,
什么?
yes?
他是个海员
A man of the sea.
一个很棒的水手
A great sailor,
直到他碰上了一个 让任何男人都苦恼的东西
until he run afoul of that which vex all men.
什么让任何男人都苦恼?
What vexes all men?
到底是什么东西?
What indeed?
- 大海 - 宝物
- The sea. - Sums.
正义与邪恶的集合
The dichotomy of good and evil.
女人
A woman.
一个他爱上的女人
He fell in love.
等等 我听说的是他爱上了大海
No, no, no, no. I heard it was the sea he fell in love with.
同样的故事 不同的版本 不过都是正确的
Same story, different versions, and all are true.
他爱上的那个女人
See, it was a woman
就如同大海般易变、残酷
as changing and harsh
无法驯服
and untamable as the sea.
他从没停止爱她
Him never stopped loving her.
可是这样的爱为他带来了极大痛苦
But the pain it cause him was too much to live with
却又不至于痛到取走他的生命
but not enough to cause him to die.
他到底把什么放在宝箱里?
What exactly did he put into the chest?
他的心
Him heart.
你是认真的还是在比喻?
Literally or figuratively?
他怎么可能真的把他的心放在宝箱里
He couldn't literally put his heart in a chest.
可能吗?
Could he?
他觉得爱得这么痛苦太不值得了
It was not worth feeling what small, fleeting joy life brings.
于是
And so
他挖出了他的心
him carve out him heart,
将它锁进了宝箱 再把宝箱藏了起来
Iock it away in a chest and hide the chest from the world.
这把钥匙
The key
他寸步不离地带在身边
he keep with him at all times.
- 你早就知道了吧 - 我不知道 我原本不知道钥匙在哪里
- You knew this. - I did not. I didn't know where the key was.
现在剩下的就是去找到"飞行荷兰人" 拿了钥匙
But now we do. All that's left is to climb aboard the Flying Dutchman, grab the key,
回到皇家港 救出你的甜心
you go back to Port Royal and save your bonnie lass, eh?
让我看看你的手
Let me see your hand.
黑斑
The black spot!
- 黑斑 - 黑斑
- The black spot! - Black spot!
我的视力还是跟以前一样好
My eyesight's as good as ever, just so you know.
我有样东西 我把它放哪儿了?
I have just the thing. Now, where did I put it?
我的小美丽 你在哪里
My little beauty, where are you?
这么长时间的混乱
Such a long time in such a mess.
戴维·琼斯不能上岸
Davy Jones cannot make port.
不能上岸 他每十年才能踏上土地一次
Cannot step on land but once every ten years.
在地上你才是安全的 杰克·斯派洛
Land is where you are safe, Jack Sparrow,
所以 你把土地带着
and so you will carry land with you.
泥土
Dirt.
- 这是一罐泥土 - 对
- This is a jar of dirt. - Yes.
这罐泥土有用吗?
Is the jar of dirt going to help?
你不想要的话就还我
If you don't want it, give it back.
- 不要 - 它会帮上忙的
- No. - Then it helps.
我们需要找到"飞行荷兰人"
It seems we have a need to find the Flying Dutchman.
预测命运
A touch of destiny.
那就是"飞行荷兰人"?
That's the Flying Dutchman?
- 看起来不怎么样 - 你看起来也不怎么样
- She doesn't look like much. - Neither do you.
别小看她
Do not underestimate her.
- 它看起来好像触礁了 - 你打算怎么办?
- Must have run afoul of the reef. - So, what's your plan, then?
我划小船过去 翻遍整艘船 直到找到你的钥匙为止
I row over, search the ship until I find your bloody key.
如果有船员呢?
And if there are crewmen?
谁挡路我就砍谁
I cut down anyone in my path.
很好 我喜欢 简单明了
I like it. Simple, easy to remember.
先生 你的战车等着你呢
Your chariot awaits you, Sire.
如果你被逮住了 就说 杰克·斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
If you do happen to get captured, just say Jack Sparrow sent you to settle his debt.
- 它能让你活命 - 祝你好运
- It might save your life. - Bon voyage!
熄灯
Douse the lamps.
水手
Sailor.
- 船长命令 扬帆 - 水手
- Hoisting the jib, Captain's orders. - Sailor!
扬起帆 掉头
Hoisting the jib. Bring up with a round turn.
没有用 你们搁浅了
There's no use. You've run aground.
不
No.
在我们下面
Beneath us.
有可怕的呼吸声
Foul breath.
求饶祈祷吧
Down on your marrowbones and pray.
退开 退开
Get back! Get back!
只剩五人活着 其他的都死了
Five men still alive. The rest have moved on.
你怕死吗?
Do you fear death?
你畏惧那黑色深渊吗?
Do you fear that dark abyss?
你的一生尽现于此
All your deeds laid bare.
你的罪行将被惩罚
All your sins punished.
我可以给你
I can offer you
逃命的机会
an escape.
别听他胡说
Don't listen to him!
你不怕死亡吗?
Do you not fear death?
我宁可冒这个险
I'll take my chances, sir.
丢下海
To the depths.
可恶
Cruel blackguard!
生命是残酷的
Life is cruel.
死后的世界难道有什么不同吗?
Why should the afterlife be any different?
我给你一个机会
I offer you a choice.
加入我的团队
Join my crew
推迟你的审判
and postpone the judgment.
你可以多活一百年
One hundred years before the mast.
你愿意加入吗?
Will ye serve?
我愿意
I will serve.
你没死 也不会死
You are neither dead nor dying.
你为何来这里?
What is your purpose here?
杰克·斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
你为何来这里?
What is your purpose here?
杰克·斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
是吗?
Did he, now?
真是个让人心动的提议
I'm sorely tempted to accept that offer.
你要还债
You have a debt to pay.
你做了"黑珍珠"的船长十三年
You've been captain of the Black Pearl for 13 years.
那是我们约好的
That was our agreement.
确切地说我只做了两年 然后就被推翻了
Technically I was only captain for two years, then I was mutinied upon.
你是个可怜的船长 但你还是船长
Then you were a poor captain, but a captain nonetheless.
这些年来你每次自我介绍时 不都自称
Have you not introduced yourself all these years
"杰克·斯派洛船长"吗?
as Captain Jack Sparrow?
我已经赔付了给你 我已经送了个人给你当水手
You have my payment. One soul to serve on your ship.
两个灵魂不能混为一谈
One soul is not equal to another.
我们已经达成了共识 接下来我们谈谈价钱吧
We've established my proposal is sound in principle. Now we're haggling over price.
价钱?
Price?
我的灵魂需要多少人来换
Just how many souls do you think my soul is worth?
一百人的灵魂
One hundred souls.
三天时间
Three days.
你真是个宝 伙计 你把那孩子送回来我们马上去办
You're a diamond, mate. Send me back the boy. I'll get started right off.
我要把这孩子留做保证金
I keep the boy. A good-faith payment.
再给我99人就好了
That leaves you only 99 more to go.
你没有遇见威尔·特纳吗?
Have you not met Will Turner?
他正直、英勇 还是个娘娘腔
He's noble, heroic, a terrific soprano.
至少可抵四个
Worth at least four.
也许三个半人
Maybe three and a half.
我有没有提到过?
And did I happen to mention
他正在热恋中
he's in love?
和一个女孩
With a girl.
即将要成婚
Due to be married.
已经订婚了
Betrothed.
硬生生把他和他的爱人拆散
Dividing him from her and her from him would only be half as cruel
不会比让他们成婚还更残酷吧?
as actually allowing them to be joined in holy matrimony. Eh?
我要留着他 你再给我99个人
I keep the boy. 99 souls.
我在想 斯派洛
But I wonder, Sparrow,
你良心能安稳吗?
can you live with this?
你能宣判一个无辜的人 一个朋友
Can you condemn an innocent man, a friend,
宣判他无期徒刑 而你自己却在享受自由吗?
to a lifetime of servitude in your name while you roam free?
是的 我没有问题
Yep. I'm good with it.
我们需要滴血...墨为盟吗?
Shall we seal it in blood? I mean ink.
三天时间
Three days.
- 吉布斯 - 是的
- Mr Gibbs. - Aye.
我突然觉得跟平常不同
I feel sullied and unusual.
你打算怎么在三天内找到99人?
And how do you intend to harvest these 99 souls in three days?
幸运的是 他并没有提及他要的是什么样的人
Fortunately, he was mum as to the condition in which these souls need be.
托图加岛
Tortuga.
这简直是侮辱 港口税 船棚费
It's an outrage. Port tariffs, berthing fees,
处理费 上帝啊 还有导航费
wharf handling and, heaven help us, pilotage.
我们真的得为东印度公司工作吗?
Are we all to work for the East lndia Trading Company, then?
船长 现在完全免费的港口只剩托图加岛了
I'm afraid, sir, Tortuga is the only free port left in these waters.
你是指那个海盗港 嗯 抱歉
A pirate port is what you mean. Well, I'm sorry.
我是个诚实的航海员 我做的是正当的生意 晚上我睡觉才安稳
An honest sailor is what I am. I make my living fair and I sleep well each night.
船长
Sir!
她想叫你做什么
She wants you to do something.
她好像在给我们什么暗示
She's trying to give a sign.
那边 找找看有什么暗示
Over there! Look for a sign!
在那边 找到了
Look, there! There it is!
- 她给的暗示 - 那是海草
- There's the sign! - That's seaweed.
- 海草也可以是个暗示吧 - 我看像是什么生物的内脏
- Seaweed can be a sign. - Looks like entrails.
- 那是不好的预兆 - 那是什么东西?
- That would be a bad sign. - What's that over there?
(托图加岛)
你为何认为自己 可以成为"黑珍珠"的一员呢?
And what makes you think you're worthy to crew the Black Pearl?
我从来没有乘过船
I've never sailed a day in me life.
我只是想趁还年轻时多看看世界
I figure I should get out, see the world while I'm still young.
非常好 请签字 下一个
You'll do. Make your mark. Next!
我太太带着我的狗 跟人跑了
My wife ran off with my dog
我已经醉了一个月
and I'm drunk for a month
现在的我对自己是死是活
and I don't give an ass rat's
已经不在乎了
if I live or die.
- 非常好 下一位 - 我知道我需要什么
- Perfect. Next! - I knowwhat I want. I knowwhat I want...
- 我只有一只手 且脚是跛的 - 这是给你乌鸦巢
- Me have one arm and a bum leg. - It's the crow's nest for you.
- 我知道我要的是什么 - 下一位
- I knowwhat I want. - Next!
我从小就想当个水手
Ever since I was a little lad, I've always wanted to sail the seas forever.
你的梦想就快实现了 请签字
Sooner than you think. Sign the roster.
多谢
Thanks very much.
- 招到几个了? - 包括刚才那四个 一共四个
- How we going? - lncluding those four, that gives us four.
你又有什么故事?
And what's your story?
我的故事
My story.
我的故事就和你的故事一样 只不过慢你一章
It's exactly the same as your story, just one chapter behind.
我为了追缉一个人 航遍了七海
I chased a man across the seven seas.
这漫长的追赶 使得我失去了我的船员
The pursuit cost me my crew,
我的军衔
my commission,
以及我的生命
and my life.
- 司令官? - 我已经不是司令官了 你没听到我说的话吗?
- Commodore? - No, not any more. Weren't you listening?
在的黎波里 我差点就捉到你们了
I nearly had you all off Tripoli.
如果不是因为那该死的飓风的话
I would have, if not for the hurricane.
天啊
Lord.
你不会是硬闯飓风吧?
You didn't try to sail through it?
我到底能不能
So, do I make your crew
加入你们?
or not?
你还没说你们要去哪里
You haven't said where you're going.
是个好地方吗?
Somewhere nice?!
我到底有没有这荣幸
So, am I worthy to serve
为杰克·斯派洛船长效劳?
under Captain Jack Sparrow?
或是我现在就杀了你
Or should I just kill you now?
你被录取了
You're hired.
对不起 老习惯改不了
Sorry. Old habits and all that.
- 小心 水手 - 你枪指的是船长
- Easy, sailor! - That's our captain you're threatening.
- 该走了 - 是
- Time to go. - Aye!
谢了 兄弟
Thanks, mate.
请继续
Carry on.
来啊 你们谁想挨揍?
Come on, then! Who wants some?
排成一列 我会一个个收拾你们
Form an orderly line and I'll have you all, one by one.
来来来 谁先来?
Come on, who's first?
我只是想享受打昏他的乐趣
I just wanted the pleasure of doing that myself.
詹姆士·诺灵顿
James Norrington.
这世界对你做了什么?
What has the world done to you?
拉起来
Heave!
- 拉起来 - 拉起来
- Heave! - Heave!
稳固桅杆 特纳
Secure the mast tackle, Mr Turner!
栓紧它
Set to it!
- 让开 - 嘿 管好你自己
- Step aside. - Hey! Mind yourself!
走开
Let go, boy!
不
No.
把他绑起来
Haul that weevil to his feet.
赏你五鞭让你知道怎么服从命令
Five lashes will remind you to stay on 'em!
- 不要 - 居然敢违抗我的命令?
- No! - lmpeding me in my duties?
- 你们都要受罚 - 罚我一个人就好
- You'll share the punishment. - I'll take it all.
你一个人?
Will you, now?
什么时候你变得这么有同情心?
And what would prompt such an act of charity?
我的儿子
My son.
他是我的儿子
He's my son.
真的好巧呀
What fortuitous circumstance be this?
你代替我来赏他五鞭吧
Five lashes be owed, I believe it is.
不 我不行
No. No, I won't!
特纳先生 只要在他背上快快抽五下
The cat's out of the bag, Mr Turner.
你打他会比我或其它人打的更不疼吧
Your issue will feel its sting, be it by the bosun's hand or your own.
不
No.
- 布舍尔 - 不要
- Bosun! - No!
便宜你了 小子
You had it easy, boy!
- 威尔 - 我不需要你的帮忙
- Will. - I don't need your help.
要不是我 你一定被打得皮开肉绽
The bosun prides himself on cleaving flesh from bone, with every swing.
这么说来你打我都是为了我好啰
So I'm to understand what you did was an act of compassion?
是的
Yes.
在你服役的这一百年 你的肉体会渐渐剥落
100 years before the mast, losing who you were, bit by bit,
直到你像可怜的威尔一样
until you end up... end up like poor Wyvern here.
一旦你宣誓为"飞行荷兰人"效忠后 这就是你必得的下场
Once you've sworn an oath to the Dutchman, there's no leaving it.
直到债务偿还
Not until your debt is paid.
我并没有宣誓
I've sworn no oath.
那你应该快点离开
You must get away.
除非我找到这个
Not until I find this.
钥匙
The key.
亡灵箱的钥匙
The dead man's chest.
你知道些什么?
What do you know of this?
用那把钥匙打开宝箱 再一刀刺进那心脏
Open the chest with the key, and stab the heart...
不不不 不能刺那心脏
No, don't stab the heart.
"飞行荷兰人"需要一个活的心脏 心脏死的话船长就死了
The Dutchman needs a living heart or there'll be no captain,
船长死了的话就没人有钥匙了
and if there's no captain, there's no one to have the key.
这么说钥匙在船长身上?
So the captain has the key?
- 钥匙在哪里? - 藏起来了
- Where is the key? - Hidden.
- 宝箱又在哪里? - 藏起来了
- Where is the chest? - Hidden.
斯派洛船长
Captain Sparrow!
来加入我的船队吗? 欢迎
Come to join me crew, lad? Welcome aboard.
我是来找我心爱的男人的
I'm here to find the man I love.
我深感荣幸 可惜大海是我最爱 也是唯一的爱
I'm deeply flattered, son, but my first and only love is the sea.
我是指威廉·特纳 斯派洛船长
Meaning William Turner, Captain Sparrow.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
把朗姆酒藏起来
Hide the rum.
这套衣服一点都不适合你 要么穿女装 要么什么都不穿
These clothes do not flatter you. It should be a dress or nothing.
- 刚好我的舱房里一件女装都没有 - 杰克
- I happen to have no dress in my cabin. - Jack.
我知道威尔来找过你 他在哪里
I know Will came to find you. Where is he?
亲爱的 我实在很不愿意告诉你
Darling, I am truly unhappy to have to tell you this, but
在一连串与我无关也无法预料的不幸事件中
through unfortunate circumstances that had nothing whatsoever to do with me,
可怜的威尔被戴维·琼斯抓去当水手了
poor Will has been press-ganged into Davy Jones's crew.
戴维·琼斯?
Davy Jones?
拜托
Oh, please.
就是"飞行荷兰人"的船长
The captain of the Flying Dutchman?
- 瞧你副德行 来我船上干吗? - 是你雇我来的
- You look awful. What are you doing here? - You hired me.
你雇佣标准这么低 这我也无能为力
I can't help it if your standards are lax.
- 你臭死了 - 杰克
- You smell funny. - Jack!
我只想找到威尔
All I want is to find Will.
你确信? 真的很想找到他?
Are you certain? Is that what you really want most?
是的
Of course.
依我看你应该找的是 一个解救威尔的办法
Because I would think you'd want to find a way to save Will most.
- 你有办法是吗? - 是这样...
- And you'd have a way of doing that? - Well,
- 有那么一个宝箱 - 哦 亲爱的
- there is a chest. - Oh, dear.
它大小不知 地点不明
A chest of unknown size and origin.
里面装的是 戴维·琼斯那颗仍然跳动的心
What contains the still-beating heart of Davy Jones.
只要拥有这宝箱
And whoever possesses that chest
就能命令琼斯做任何事
possesses the leverage to command Jones to do whatever it is he or she wants,
包括从困境中解救勇敢的威尔
including saving brave William from his grim fate.
你不会真的相信他这一套吧?
You don't actually believe him, do you?
怎么才能找到它呢?
Howwould we find it?
用这个
With this.
我这罗盘世上独一无二
My compass is unique.
独一无二? 你是说它失灵了吧?
"Unique" here having the meaning of "broken".
没错 这个罗盘不会指向北
True enough, this compass does not point north.
那它指向哪?
Where does it point?
它会指向这世上你最想要的东西
It points to the thing you want most in this world.
哦 杰克
Jack.
- 这是真的吗? - 句句属实 亲爱的
- Are you telling the truth? - Every word, love.
这世上你最想要的就是...
And what you want most in this world
戴维·琼斯的亡灵箱 是吗?
is to find the chest of Davy Jones, is it not?
- 去救威尔 - 先找到戴维·琼斯的亡灵箱
- To save Will. - By finding the chest of Davy Jones.
- 吉布斯先生 - 船长
- Mr Gibbs! - Cap'n.
- 有航向了 - 终于有了
- We have our heading. - Finally!
割断缆绳 向罗盘指示的方向前进 起锚 扬帆
Cast off those lines. Weigh anchor and crowd that canvas!
斯旺小姐
Miss Swann.
欢迎加入我们的队伍 前司令官
Welcome to the crew, former commodore.
我们得通晓世界地理
There's something to knowing the exact shape of the world and one's place in it.
我向你保证 这些完全没有必要
I assure you, these are not necessary.
我以为你关心你女儿的下落
I thought you'd be interested in the whereabouts of your daughter.
- 你有她的消息吗? - 不久前在托图加岛上出现过
- You have news of her? - Most recently seen on Tortuga,
后来上了海盗杰克·斯派洛的贼船
and then left in the company of a known pirate, Jack Sparrow,
这船上聚集的都是些法外之徒
and other fugitives from justice.
法!哪里还有王法!
"Justice"? Hardly.
其中还包括这把剑的主人
Including the previous owner of this sword, I believe.
我已经派出船只 正义将被重新伸张
Our ships are in pursuit. Justice will be dispensed by cannonade and cutlass,
到时候剑拔弩张 枪炮无眼
and all manner of remorseless pieces of metal.
依我看 那贼船上的人恐怕性命难保
I find it distasteful to even contemplate the horror facing all those on board.
你想从我这里得到什么?
What do you want from me?
你的地方管辖权 加上你在伦敦的影响力
Your authority as governor, your influence in London,
并且要你效忠于东印度公司
and your loyalty to the East lndia Trading Company.
是效忠于你吧?
To you, you mean.
要我帮你打开手铐吗?
Shall I remove these shackles?
尽可能地帮我找女儿
Do what you can for my daughter.
你看 只要价位合适 几乎任何人都可以被收买
So you see, Mercer, every man has a price he will willingly accept.
哪怕是他从不曾打算出卖的东西
Even for what he hoped never to sell.
我赌十年
I wager ten years.
跟你 我也赌十年
I'll match ten years.
好吧
Agreed.
你知道怎么玩么?
Wondering how it's played?
- 知道 - 开!
- I understand. - Liar!
这是一场欺诈的赌博 你赌所有骰子的点数 不光是自己的
It's a game of deception. But your bet includes all the dice, not just your own.
- 赌注是什么? - 我们唯一拥有的东西
- What are they wagering? - The only thing we have.
在船上服侍的年份
Years of service.
- 跟谁都可以对赌? - 是的 都可以
- So any crew member can be challenged? - Aye. Anyone.
我要和戴维·琼斯赌
I challenge Davy Jones.
我接受了
I accept, mate.
- 你的赌注呢? - 我的灵魂 永远的被奴役
- The stakes? - My soul. An eternity of servitude.
不!
No!
你想赢什么?
Against?
我要这个
I want this.
- 你是怎么知道这钥匙的? - 这与赌局无关 不是吗?
- How do you know of the key? - That's not part of the game, is it?
你现在放弃还不迟
You can still walk away.
- 这算什么? - 我也要赌 和他的赌注一样
- What's this? - I'm in. Matching his wager.
不!别这样
No! Don't do this.
游戏已经开始了
The die is cast.
我猜3个二
I bid three twos.
该你了 船长
It's your bid, Captain.
4个四
Four fours.
4个五
Four fives.
6个三
Six threes.
7个五
Seven fives.
8个五
Eight fives.
欢迎入队 年青人
Welcome to the crew, lad.
12个五
Twelve fives.
叫我开 要不就继续加
Call me a liar, or up the bid.
想让我放弃 承认自己输了?
And be called a liar myself for my trouble?
系带王比尔 你输了 今生今世都要呆在这船上
Bootstrap Bill, you're a liar and you will spend an eternity on this ship.
特纳先生 想上岸的话随你
Master Turner, feel free to go ashore
不过要等到我们下次靠岸喽!
the very next time we make port!
你真傻 为什么要这么做?
Fool. Why did you do that?
我不能让你输
I couldn't let you lose.
关键并不在于输赢
It was never about winning or losing.
是钥匙
The key.
你只是想知道钥匙藏在哪儿
You just wanted to know where it was.
船长让我来换你的班
Captain says I'm to relieve you.
船长的命令
Captain's orders.
把这个也拿着
Here. Take this, too.
回到岸上去 不要再下海了
Now, get yourself to land, and stay there.
我命中注定要死在海上的
It was always in my blood to die at sea.
但我不希望你也有同样的命运
It was not a fate I ever wanted for you.
你也可以不选择如此命运
It's not a fate you had to choose for yourself, either.
我当初是不得已 才抛弃你去当海盗的
Aye. I could say I did what I had to, when I left you to go pirating.
但是对你说谎并不是我所想要的
But it would taste a lie to say it wasn't what I wanted.
威尔 你不欠我什么
You owe me nothing, Will.
走吧
Now go.
他们会知道是你帮了我
They'll know you helped me.
他们还能把我怎么样呢?
What more can they do to me?
我以这把匕首向你保证
I take this with a promise.
我会把你从琼斯的魔爪中救出来
I'll find a way to sever Jones's hold on you,
不用这匕首刺入他的心绝不罢休
and not rest until this blade pierces his heart.
我永远不会抛弃你
I will not abandon you.
我发誓
I promise.
- 贝克特? - 是的 他们都签字了
- Beckett? - Yes, they're signed.
东印度公司的贝克特勋爵
Lord Cutler Beckett of the East lndia Trading Company.
威尔在为贝克特勋爵效劳! 他可一个字也没提过
Will was working for Beckett and never said a word.
贝克特想要你的罗盘 目的只有一个
Beckett wants the compass. Only one reason for that.
没错
Of course.
- 他想得到亡灵箱 - 没错 他的确提到过什么宝箱的
- He wants the chest. - Yes, he did say something about a chest.
如果东印度公司控制了亡灵箱 就等于控制了整个大海
If the company controls the chest, they controls the sea.
- 大海将面临灾难 亲爱的 - 还有厄运
- A truly discomfiting notion, love. - And bad.
天下每个海盗的厄运
Bad for every mother's son what calls himself a pirate.
我们需要加快速度
I think there's a bit more speed to be coaxed from these sails.
升船头帆!
Brace the foreyard!
你能告诉我是怎么得到这东西的吗?
Might I enquire as to how you came by these?
- 说服力 - 是友好的那种么?
- Persuasion. - Friendly?
完全不是
Decidedly not.
威尔为了它煞费苦心 你却轻而易举就得到了 赦免令
Will strikes a deal, yet you were the one with the prize, full pardon.
“作为大英帝国授权的私掠船长
"Commission as a privateer on behalf of England
替东印度公司服务”
and the East lndia Trading Company."
你以为这点东西就能收买我了
As if I could be bought for such a low price.
- 那你把赦免令还给我 - 不行
- Jack, the letters, give them back. - No.
你得先说服我
Persuade me.
你知道威尔教过我如何用剑吗?
You do know Will taught me how to handle a sword?
我说过了 要先说服我
As I said, persuade me.
真是奇怪啊
It's a curious thing.
我曾经愿意舍弃一切 只想换来你对我动情一笑
There was a time I would have wanted you to look like that while thinking about me.
- 我不懂你的意思 - 我知道你懂
- I don't know what you mean. - I think you do.
别瞎猜 我只是信任他而已
Don't be absurd. I trust him, that's all.
你那未婚夫怎么会无缘无故
So you never wondered how your latest fiance
沦落到"飞行的荷兰人"上呢?
ended up on the Flying Dutchman in the first place?
公海上突然出现一艘救生艇
Strange to come upon a longboat so far out in open water.
你们最好开全速 越快越好
Just put as many leagues behind us as you can. As fast as you can.
我们要逃避什么吗?
And what are we running from?
这套女装 哪儿来的?
That dress. Where did you get it?
船上找到的
It was found aboard the ship.
船员们认为这是幽灵带来的 某种坏运气的征兆
The crew thought it was a spirit bringing some omen of ill-fate.
- 胡说八道 - 是啊 一派胡言
- That's foolish. - Yes. Exceedingly foolish.
它可给我们带来了好运 幽灵告诉我们"去托图加岛"
It brought good fortune. The spirit told us, "Pull in at Tortuga",
我们在那里挣了一大笔钱
and we made a nice bit of profit there.
像魔术一样
Off the books, of course.
我猜你们船员中有人在托图加岛离船了
I imagine some of your crew may have jumped ship there.
- 你为什么这么问? - 船长!一艘船向我们驶来
- Why do you ask? - Captain! A ship's been spotted.
- 旗帜什么颜色? - 没有旗帜
- Colours? - She isn't flying any.
- 是海盗 - 没错
- Pirates. - Or worse.
你给我挣大眼睛好好瞧着
You will watch this.
欢声笑语顿然不再
Let no joyful voice be heard!
仰天绝望尝尽悲哀
Let no man look up at the sky with hope.
今天让他们见识什么叫厉害
And let this day be cursed by we who ready to wake
召唤挪威海怪
the kraken.
不!
No!
我把这船人都害了
I've doomed us all.
是"飞行的荷兰人"
It's the Flying Dutchman!
他妈的这是怎么了?
Mother Carey's chickens! What happened?
一定是触礁了
Must have hit a reef.
松舵!左满舵然后右满舵
Free the rudder! Hard to port then hard to starboard.
- 松舵! - 左满舵!
- Free the rudder! - Hard to port!
- 挪威海怪! - 挪威海怪!
- Kraken! - Kraken!
在这里!拿去吧!
Here it is! Take it!
拿去吧!
Take it!
没看到那小子 一定是被大海吞噬了
The boy's not here. He must have been claimed by the sea.
我就是大海
I am the sea.
给你点时间哀悼
You need time alone with your thoughts.
- 布羚! - 幸存者怎么办?
- Brig! - What of the survivors?
无一幸存
There are no survivors.
亡灵箱已经不再安全了 向克鲁斯岛出发
The chest is no longer safe. Chart a course to lsla Cruces.
一定要先到达 不然有你们受的
Get me there first, or there'll be the devil to pay.
"先到达"?
"First"?
是谁把那小贼安排在我船上?
Who sent that thieving charlatan onto my ship?
是谁告诉他有关钥匙的事?
Who told him of the key?
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
我对女人的直觉告诉我你心情烦躁
My intuitive sense of the female creature informs me that you are troubled.
我只是在想我现在本该结婚了的
I just thought I'd be married by now.
我为结婚做了那么多的准备
I'm so ready to be married.
你知道...
You know...
莉齐 我是船长
Lizzie, I am captain of a ship,
作为一名船长 我必须完成"结啊婚"的任务
and being captain of a ship, I could in fact perform a "marr-i-age" right here.
就在这甲板上
Right on this deck.
立即完成
Right now.
不行 谢谢
No, thank you.
为什么不?
Why not?
我们是那么的相似 你和我 我和你
We are very much alike, you and l. I and you. Us.
除了荣誉感 行为准则和道德体系
Except for a sense of honour and decency and a moral centre.
还有个人卫生
And personal hygiene.
都是小事
Trifles.
你早晚会跟我当海盗的
You will come over to my side. I know it.
- 你好像很有把握 - 一个词 亲爱的 好奇心
- You seem very certain. - One word, love. Curiosity.
你渴望自由
You long for freedom.
渴望能做自己想做的事情 这是你的个性
You long to do what you want to do because you want it.
冲动而且执着
To act on selfish impulse.
你想去亲身体验一下
You want to see what it's like.
早晚有一天 你将无法抗拒
One day, you won't be able to resist.
为什么你的罗盘失灵了?
Why doesn't your compass work?
我的罗盘工作得很好
My compass works fine.
因为你和我一样
Because you and I are alike,
都有善良的一面
and there will come a moment when you have a chance to show it.
- 它会找时机表现出来的 - 我很珍惜这种时机
- To do the right thing. - I love those moments.
每当这种时机降临时 我总会挥手相送
I like to wave at them as they pass by.
你将有机会做勇敢正义之事
You'll have the chance to do something... something courageous.
到那时 你会发现
And when you do, you'll discover something.
你原来是个好人
That you're a good man.
所有证据显示 事实恰恰相反
All evidence to the contrary.
我对你有信心
I have faith in you.
- 想知道为什么吗? - 那就说吧 小宝贝
- Want to know why? - Do tell, dearie.
好奇心
Curiosity.
你渴望得到一个机会
You're going to want it.
受人钦佩 得到嘉奖
A chance to be admired and gain the rewards that follow.
你将无法抗拒
You won't be able to resist.
你会想去亲身体验一下
You're going to want to know what it tastes like.
我的确想亲身体验一下
I do want to knowwhat it tastes like.
但是 身为一个好人
But, seeing as you're a good man,
我知道你不会趁人之危
I know that you'd never put me in a position that would compromise my honour.
我为你自豪 杰克
I'm proud of you, Jack.
陆地!
Land, ho!
我需要我那罐土
I want my jar of dirt.
- 你划的太快了 - 是你划的太慢了
- You're pulling too fast. - You're pulling too slow.
- 我们都不想挪威海怪追上我们 - 我是在为紧急关头攒把力
- We don't want the kraken to catch us. - I'm saving me strength for when it comes.
才不叫"挪威海兽"呢 别人都它叫"挪威海贼"
And I don't think it's "kracken" anyways. I always heard it said "krayken".
A发长音?
With a long a?
不 不 不 "挪威海王"是北欧那边的发音
No, no, no... "Krocken" is how it's pronounced in Scandinavian,
"挪威海兽"更接近一点
and "kracken" is closer to that.
我们可不在北欧 不是吗? "挪威海贼"
We ain't Scandinavians, are we? "Krayken."
它不过是个神话中的动物 我想怎样称乎就怎样称乎
It's a mythological creature. I can calls it what I wants.
把船看好 注意潮水
Guard the boat. Mind the tide.
别碰我那罐土
Don't touch my dirt.
它坏了 根本就不能指向你想要的东西
This doesn't work. And it certainly doesn't show you what you want most.
当然能 你就坐在上面
Yes, it does. You're sitting on it.
- 你说什么? - 起来
- Beg pardon? - Move.
- "把船看好!""注意潮水!" - 我要参加马戏团
- "Guard the boat!" "Mind the tide!" - I could join the circus.
要不要我给你擦鞋啊 先生?
Mind if I shine your shoes, sir?
他们已经到了 我已经近十年不能上岸了
They're here. And I cannot step foot on land again for near of a decade.
你相信我们能做好吧?
You'll trust us to act in your stead?
我要你们相信如果失败会有什么后果!
I'll trust you to know what awaits you should you fail!
- 下潜 马上! - 下潜!
- Down, then! - Down!
是真的
It's real.
你还真说了句实话
You actually were telling the truth.
我说过很多实话 不知为什么当人们发现时总是会惊讶
I do that quite a lot, yet people are always surprised.
这其中是有原因的
With good reason!
威尔!
Will!
你没事!谢天谢地 我是来找你的!
You're all right! Thank God! I came to find you!
你怎么到这来的?
How did you get here?
我捉住一对海龟 绑在双脚上
Sea turtles, mate. A pair of them, strapped to my feet.
游过来不容易 对吧?
Not so easy, is it?
- 不过我还得好好谢谢你 杰克 - 真的么?
- But I do owe you thanks, Jack. - You do?
即使是你先骗我上了戴维·琼斯的船 让我去还你的债
After you tricked me onto that ship to square your debt with Jones...
- 什么? - 什么?
- What? - What?
我才能和我父亲重聚
..I was reunited with my father.
哦 不必客气
Well, you're welcome, then.
你对我说的每件事每个字都是谎言
Everything you said to me, every word was a lie!
没错
Pretty much.
恶习难改 亲爱的
Time and tide, love.
哎! 你想干什么?
Oi! What are you doing?
我要杀了琼斯
I'm going to kill Jones.
这可不行 威廉
Can't let you do that, William.
如果琼斯死了 谁还能驾驭他那只怪兽?
Cos if Jones is dead, who's to call his terrible beastie off the hunt, eh?
现在 如果你不介意
Now, if you please.
把钥匙给我
The key.
我要兑现我的诺言 杰克
I keep the promises I make, Jack.
我要还父亲的自由 我希望你能目睹一切
I intend to free my father. I hope you're here to see it.
我也不能让你那么做 很抱歉
I can't let you do that either. So sorry.
我就知道你早晚会站在我这一边的
I knew you'd warm up to me eventually.
贝克特勋爵渴望得到这箱子里的东西
Lord Beckett desires the content of that chest.
一旦给他带回去 我将重新拥有一切
I deliver it, I get my life back.
阴险的野心
The dark side of ambition.
我认为是赎罪的曙光
I prefer to see it as the promise of redemption.
住手!
Stop it!
威尔!
Will!
- 看好箱子! - 不!
- Guard the chest! - No!
太野蛮了! 没门儿...
This is barbaric! This is no way for grown men to...
好吧!我们都拔出剑来互相攻击
Fine! Let's just haul out our swords and start banging away at each other.
这样能解决所有的事情! 我受够了!
That will solve everything! I've had it!
我受够了你们这些软脚虾 烂酒鬼 臭海盗
I've had it with wobbly-legged, rum-soaked pirates!
- 这到底是怎么回事儿啊? - 他们都想独吞箱子
- How'd this go all screwy? - Well, each wants the chest for hisself.
诺灵顿想拿回去立功赎罪
Mr Norrington, I think, is trying to regain a bit of honour,
杰克想还给琼斯 挽回面子
old Jack's looking to trade it, save his own skin,
特纳想兑现诺言
then Turner, there, I think he's trying to settle some unresolved business
拯救他变成水鬼的父亲
'twixt him and his twice-cursed pirate father.
- 悲哀 - 真是疯子!
- Sad. - This is madness!
那箱子一定价值不菲
That chest must be worth more than a shiny penny.
是祸根
Terrible temptation.
假如我们还有点良知 就应该为他们除去这罪魁祸首
If we was any kind of decent, we'd remove temptation from their path.
够了!
Enough!
太热了!
The heat!
混蛋!
Bugger!
抱歉了 特纳先生
By your leave, Mr Turner.
抱歉了 诺灵顿先生
By your leave, Mr Norrington.
抱歉 我得先杀了这个毁了我一生幸福的人
Do excuse me while I kill the man who ruined my life.
- 请便 - 让我们先核实这说法
- Be my guest. - Let us examine that claim for a moment.
到底是谁 在你把臭名昭著的海盗 放心地关到监牢的时候
Who was it, that at the very moment you had a notorious pirate safely behind bars,
乘机放走了海盗 把你的心上人据为己有?
saw fit to free said pirate and take your dearly beloved all to hisself?
所以 到底是谁的错?
So whose fault is it, really,
让你沦落为酗酒的低等水手 听命于海盗?
that you've ended up a rum-pot deckhand what takes orders from pirates?
够了!
Enough!
不幸的是 特纳先生 他是对的!
Unfortunately, Mr Turner, he's right!
我还是支持你的 伙计!
Still rooting for you, mate.
我们拿到了!
We got it! We got it! We got it!
你好啊 小妹妹
Hello, poppet.
冲啊!冲啊!
Come on, run!
- 剑! - 剑!剑!
- Sword! - Sword! Sword!
剑!
Sword!
跟着我的声音 跟着我的声音
Follow my voice. Follow my voice.
往左...不 转回去
To the left... no, turn around.
往右点
Go to the right.
不 那是颗树
No, that's a tree.
闭嘴
Shut it.
这罐土!
Jar of dirt!
对了
Right.
我们得到了!
We've got it!
来吧 特纳!
Come on, Turner!
让他躺那儿! 除非你要用他砸人
Leave him lie! Unless you plan on using him to hit something with.
- 我们逃不掉了 - 带着箱子就无法脱身
- We're not getting out of this. - Not with the chest.
上船
Into the boat.
- 你疯了! - 不要等我
- You're mad! - Don't wait for me.
- 我说我们该尊重他的临终愿望 - 对!
- I say we respect his final wish. - Aye!
你的勇敢算是白搭了
Your bravery is wasted.
我会从你冰冷尸体的手中拿过亡灵箱
I shall pry the chest away from your cold, dead hands.
拿去吧!
Here you go!
臭海盗!
Pirates!
- 亡灵箱怎么样了? - 诺灵顿带着它引开了他们
- What happened to the chest? - Norrington took it to draw them off.
- 你拉得太用力! - 你用力得不够!
- You're pulling too hard! - You ain't pulling hard enough!
- 司令官哪里去了? - 落在后面了
- Where's the commodore? - Fell behind.
让我为他祈祷
My prayers be with him.
不过还是要节哀顺变!
Best not wallow in our grief.
幸好你回来了 毫发无伤
The bright side is you're back, and made it off free and clear.
天父在上 保佑我们!
Lord on high, deliver us.
我来处理这事 伙计
I'll handle this, mate.
死鱼脸!
Oi, fishface!
丢东西了吧?
Lose something? Eh? Scungilli!
没事!
Got it!
来谈判的吧? 你个欠揍的家伙
Come to negotiate, eh, have you, you slimy git?
看看我手上是啥
Look what I got.
我有一罐土 我有一罐土
I got a jar of dirt. I got a jar of dirt
猜猜里面是什么?
And guess what's inside it?
够了!
Enough!
- 右满舵 - 右满舵!
- Hard to starboard. - Hard to starboard!
升船头帆!
Brace up the foreyard!
右满舵!
Hard to starboard!
把他心爱的珍珠号送回地狱去
Send his beloved Pearl back to the depths.
敌火来袭!敌火来袭!
She's on us! She's on us!
- 让他们尝尝三联炮 - 是 船长
- Let them taste the triple guns. - Aye, Captain.
绑牢固了!
Make fast!
加油啊 亲爱的! 让我们看看你的实力!
Go on, me darling! Show us what you've got!
快点儿!
Come on, girl!
- 它被甩掉了 - 对 我们把它甩掉了
- She's falling behind! - Aye. We've got her!
- 我们的船快? - 逆风的话 他们快
- We're the faster? - Against the wind, the Dutchman beats us.
- 不过现在顺风... - 我们占优势
- But with the wind... - We rob her advantage.
对
Aye.
我们超出射程了
We're out of range!
停止追击 降下帆!
Break off pursuit, run her light and douse canvas!
我们放弃了?
We're giving up, sir?
他们放弃了!
They're giving up!
我父亲在那条船上
My father is on that ship.
我们能赢 我们应该回头战斗
We can take her. We should turn and fight.
能谈判时干吗要战斗? 只需要有足够的优势就行了
Why fight when you can negotiate? All one needs is the proper leverage.
去哪儿了? "砰-砰"去哪儿了?
Where is it? Where is the thump-thump?
我们肯定撞到礁石了!
We must have hit a reef!
不 那不是礁石! 离开船舷!
No. It's not a reef! Get away from the rail!
- 是什么东西? - 是挪威海怪
- What is it? - The kraken.
- 准备战斗! - 拿好枪!保护桅杆!
- To arms! - Load guns! Defend the mast!
它会从底下攻击 上炮位 等我信号!
It'll attack the starboard. Run out the cannons and hold for my signal!
放松点 伙计们!
Easy, boys!
威尔?
Will?
稳住!稳住
Steady! Steady.
- 威尔! - 稳住!稳住
- Will! - Hold. Hold.
我们等得够久了
I think we've held fire long enough.
- 威尔! - 开火!
- Will! - Fire!
- 它会回来的 我们得离船 - 没有小艇了
- lt'll be back. We have to get off the ship. - There's no boats.
拉起壁炉! 把所有火药放进货舱的网兜!
Pull the grates. Get all the gunpowder onto the net in the cargo hold!
- 不管怎样 不要射失 - 等你准备好我就开枪
- Whatever you do, don't miss. - As soon as you're clear.
我们火药不足 只有六桶了!
We are short-stocked on gunpowder! Six barrels!
快点儿!
Hurry up!
- 火药只有半打了! - 那就装郎姆酒
- There's only six kegs of powder! - Then load the rum.
好吧!郎姆酒也上!
Aye, the rum too!
赶紧!
Step to!
你这个懦夫
You coward.
不太妙
Not good.
- 拉上去! - 拉!
- Haul away! - Heave!
- 使劲拉上去! - 用尽全力!
- Heave like you're being paid for it! - Put your backs into it!
- 我抓住你了!我抓住你了! - 不要抛弃我!
- I got you! I got you! - Don't let me go!
- 我不会抛弃你的! - 向我开枪!
- I won't let you go! - Shoot me!
- 准备好了? - 往上走!往上走!
- Clear? - Higher! Higher!
这边!快来啊!
Here! Come on!
来抓我 我在这里!
Come and get me. I'm over here!
快!
Come on!
开枪 伊丽莎白 开枪!
Shoot! Elizabeth, shoot!
我们干掉它了吗?
Did we kill it?
没有 我们只是激怒了它
No. We just made it angry.
我们还没解脱 船长 下命令!
We're not out of this yet. Captain, orders!
弃船 上小艇
Abandon ship. Into the longboat.
杰克!这是珍珠号
Jack. The Pearl.
她只是条船 伙计
She's only a ship, mate.
他是对的 我们必需登陆
He's right. We have to head for land.
- 还有很宽的水面 - 还很宽啊
- It's a lot of open water. - It's a lot ofwater.
我们必需试试 如果它要毁掉珍珠号 我们还能逃脱
We have to try. We can get away as it takes down the Pearl.
弃船
Abandon ship.
放弃船 或者放弃希望
Abandon ship or abandon hope.
谢谢你 杰克
Thank you, Jack.
我们还没有脱身呢 亲爱的
We're not free yet, love.
你回来了
You came back.
我就知道你是个好人
I always knew you were a good man.
准备跳吧 没时间可以浪费了
Prepare to cast off. There's no time to lose.
赶快 威尔 往下走
Come on, Will. Step to!
它是在追杀你 不是这船
It's after you, not the ship.
不是我们
It's not us.
只有这个办法 你明白吗?
This is the only way, don't you see?
我不觉得内疚
I'm not sorry.
你这个海盗
Pirate.
杰克在哪?
Where's Jack?
他决定留下 给我们个机会
He elected to stay behind to give us a chance.
出发!
Go!
混蛋 混蛋 混蛋
Bugger. Bugger, bugger.
快!
Come on!
正好 快点
Just got it. Come on.
还不算太糟
Not so bad.
你好 小怪兽
Hello, beastie.
杰克·斯派洛 我们的帐一笔勾销了
Jack Sparrow, our debt is settled.
船长与船同沉
The captain goes down with his ship.
就算杰克·斯派洛也不能战胜魔鬼
Turns out not even Jack Sparrow can best the devil.
打开亡灵箱
Open the chest.
打开亡灵箱 我要亲眼看到!
Open the chest. I need to see it!
该死的 杰克·斯派洛!
Damn you, Jack Sparrow!
我们最后一条船回来了
The last of our ships is returned.
亡灵箱有何消息?
Is there any news on the chest?
没有 不过在海上救起一个人
None. But one of the ships did pick up a man adrift at sea.
他身上有这个
He had these.
我冒昧地填上了我的名字
I took the liberty of filling in my name.
你想要的话 就得有东西来交换
If you intend to claim these, then you must have something to trade.
你拿到罗盘了?
Do you have the compass?
比那更好
Better.
戴维·琼斯的心脏
The heart of Davy Jones.
酒可御寒
Against the cold
也能解忧
and the sorrow.
真是遗憾
It's a shame.
我知道你以为只要有了黑珍珠号
I know you're thinking that with the Pearl
就可以去擒住恶魔 救回你父亲的灵魂
you could have captured the devil and set free your father's soul.
已经无关紧要了
Doesn't matter now.
珍珠号完蛋了
The Pearl is gone,
连同它的船长
along with its captain.
对
Aye.
这世界已经灰暗了一点
And already the world seems a bit less bright.
他一直都在欺骗我们
He fooled us all right till the end,
但最后他的良心还是胜出了
but I guess that honest streak finally won out.
为杰克·斯派洛干杯!
To Jack Sparrow.
- 再也不会有第二个杰克船长了 - 他是位绅士
- Never another like Captain Jack. - He was a gentleman of fortune, he was.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
如果有什么可以救他回来的
If there was anything could be done to bring him back...
- 伊丽莎白 - 你会去做吗?
- Elizabeth. - Would you do it?
你会去做么?
What would you...
你们都愿做么 嗯?
What would any of you be willing to do, hm?
你们会航行到天涯海角
Would you sail to the ends of the Earth and beyond
去找回杰克和无价的珍珠号?
to fetch back witty Jack and him precious Pearl?
是
Aye.
Yes.
是
Aye.
那好
All right.
如果想去奇异而又充满牛鬼蛇神的天涯海角
But if you go and brave the weird and haunted shores at world's end,
你们就需要一位称职的船长
then you will need a captain who knows those waters.
说 我的船怎么样了?
So tell me, what's become of my ship?